Alexis Echemendia

Game developer, Animator, 3d Generalist

Boca Raton, FL - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Alexis-Echemendia/a55f4a4f249899a1

Unity3d developer for games, mix reality and virtual reality application.

3D Generalist with 14 years of experience in 3D art.

Trained in 3d characters animation for television and video games. Extensive knowledge in softwares Autodesk 3dsmax, Autodesk Maya and Blender.

Knowledge in 3d modeling, uv, texturing, lighting, rigging, animation, and rendering.

Script development for modeling and animation tools.

Strong knowledge in rigging of characters in Blender.

Knowledge in programming languages C #, C ++, Python, ActionScript3.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Character Animator

Unfold Games - December 2016 to Present

Character Animator of the DarqGame.

Animator, 3d Generalist

Animation Studios ICAIC - Havana, CU - 2013 to 2016

The first job in the Animation Studios at ICAIC was to teach character animation using Blender.

- Animator, rigger, illuminator and renderer in network in the first 3d short animated movie using free software called "Close".
- Animator, rigger, illuminator and network renderer, in the animated series 3d "El Reino de la Ortografía (The kingdom of spelling)" for children.
- Animator in the presentation of the programmed "Cuadro a cuadro (Frame by Frame)" very liked by the Cuban public.
- Animator for the series "Tutu" co-production Cuba-Spain, also occupy the position of technical director in the middle of the

production.

- Technical director, rigger and animator of all the characters in the video game "Chaos Numérico" still in production.
- Script development to provide solutions to artists and designers.

Lead Programmer and designer

Animation Studios ICAIC - Havana, CU - 2013 to 2014

Designer and programmer of the Show-Run-Virtual of the products of the UCI. Sample 3d content on the web. Modeling, animation and programming frontend and backend.

Lead Designer, ICVT

VE - 2011 to 2012

Develop multimedia to represent the operation of drill holes.

Modeling, texturing, animation, simulation of fluids, motion graphic designer.

Character Animator

UCI - Havana, CU - 2008 to 2009

Modeling, texturing buildings and spaces corresponding to the Virtual tour of the University of Computer Science, Cuba. Also modeling character, rigging and animation the npc.

Modeling Supervisor, UCI

Havana, CU - 2007 to 2008

Monitor the environment of video games and cars. Model some cars.

EDUCATION

Dipl in 3D Animation

Centre for Development of Advanced Computing - Chandigard, India February 2010 to April 2010

Computer System Engineer in profile in video games

Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas - Cuba, LA September 2001 to July 2007

SKILLS

3D Studio Max (10+ years), Maya (5 years), Blender (10+ years), Photoshop (10+ years), After Effects (1 year), C# (5 years), Unity3D (5 years), Microsoft Office (10+ years), 3D character animation (10+ years), 3D modeling, uv, and texturing (10+ years), Python scripting (1 year), Rigging in Blender (10+ years), Unity3d asset management and programming (5 years), Microsoft Office (10+ years), HTML 5 (10+ years), CSS3 (10+ years), C++ (3 years), Javascript (3 years)

LINKS

https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B5Q3kl 3oYd c1RhNkl4ZU5tVjg

https://www.assetstore.unity3d.com/en/#!/content/62180

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9ncbQ21794Q

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9tH9SgHsLtM

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- -Modeling Supervisor in the first video-game for Racing Game Machine exposed in Lenin Park, Cuba ("Rápido y Curioso").
- -Technical director, animator and illuminator in the first short 3d developed with free tools in Cuba (Close).
- -Technical director and animator in the first full animated series co-production Cuba-Spain (Tutu).